Some of the tools we use as a police officer, the main one is the computer.
We write reports all the time on pretty much everything we do.
We have to put in a little note whether it's, I unlocked the door to a car whatever it might be.
The computer is probably the number one thing we use all the time.
And so it's good to be proficient with the computer, know how to type.
And each department may have a program they used to write their reports on.
That's just a matter of getting with the department and learning what program it is and how it works, but the computer is the number one thing we use.
And now with that computer you can look up lots of different things, you can get on the websites, look at as far as the county booking sheets and things like that to find out where people live or some of our suspects are and the computer is a great tool that you can use, not even being out in the car you can track someone down through the computer programs.
As law enforcement has we can search different things that the average person won't be able to search because of our access we have.
And so the computer is a great tool as far as trying to track down suspects or people of interest.
Some of the other tools that we use each day is we have, we carry with us, we don't use them each day.
We have our pistols we use and we have our tasers and with that you have to be certified with our pistol you have to be certified each year.
Make sure we can pass the qualification.
If we can't then there is some problems and they need to work on that are, we can't be a police officers.
And so with the tasers you need to know, that's a great tool.
It prevents officers from getting hurt as well as the suspect that's fighting with this from getting hurt.
We are able to use the taser and they don't get hurt and we don't get hurt and things work out a lot better that way.
And so those you need to be certified in, how to use them, the proper way to use them for liability.
And so as a police officer there's many tools and then with that you need to be certified and keep up your certification each year to prevent any lawsuits or anything like that that may occur.
As far as vehicles, tools we use, we have chargers.
The Pleasant Grove Police Department and we have some explorers.
Those are great tools we have, also need to be certified with them.
Go to the driving range and make sure that you are up to par, we know our cars and if situations happen that we can handle our cars safely.
As far as there is different areas as a patrolman you can be involved in the motorcycles.
If a person has an interest and your department has motorcycles, if you are interested in that, each department is different.
You can get on a motorcycle once you go through the training and be in the traffic enforcement as far as writing tickets and patrolling the high density areas to try to slow cars down.
And some of the officers love it.
And I'm not a big fan of it, I probably crash but anyway it's all up to the person.
The officer there, but anyway it's, the officers have a good time with the motors.